Xiao (Brandon) Han

Desk 01, 01BB01, University of Surrey, Guildford, Surrey, GU2 7XH, United Kingdom

🛘 (+44) 07529989025 | 🔀 xiao.han@surrey.ac.uk | 🌴 brandonhan.uk | 🖸 GitHub | 🛅 LinkedIn | 🎓 GoogleScholar

Research Interests

I am broadly interested in the field of Deep Learning. My current research interest lies in the intersection between Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing (i.e., vision-language). My research goal is to build multi-modal Al systems that can be used in real-world applications (e.g., e-commerce platform). My expertise includes but is not limited to vision-language pre-training and (parameter-efficient) adaptation, many vision-language tasks (e.g., cross-modal retrieval, text-guided image retrieval, image captioning, text-based/guided image generation/editing), and some specific tasks (e.g., person ReID).

Education

University of Surrey Guildford, UK

Ph.D. STUDENT Jan. 2021 - Present (Jan. 2024)

- Major in Vision and Signal Processing at Centre for Vision, Speech and Signal Processing (CVSSP)
- Supervisors: Prof. Tao Xiang (principal) and Prof. Yi-Zhe Song
- Fully funded by University of Surrey FEPS/iFlyTek Ph.D. Scholarship
- Thesis Title (tentative): Fine-Grained Multimodal Deep Learning

Zhejiang University Hangzhou, China Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020 **BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING**

- Major in Information Engineering at College of Information Science and Electronic Engineering (ISEE)
- Cumulative GPA: 3.92 / 4.00 (88.13 / 100), Third-year GPA: 3.94 / 4.00 (89.46 / 100)
- Thesis Title: Deep Learning-Based Features Prediction for Mass Spectrometry of Protein

Non-Degree Academic Experiences:

Visiting student with Dr. Li Zhang at ZVG, Fudan University	Shanghai, China
Research assistant with Dr. Changbin Yu at AiR, Westlake University	Hangzhou, China
Visiting student with Prof. L. Jay Guo at EECS, University of Michigan	Ann Arbor, MI, USA
Exchange student with iESR program at University of Notre Dame	South Bend, IN, USA
	Research assistant with Dr. Changbin Yu at AiR, Westlake University Visiting student with Prof. L. Jay Guo at EECS, University of Michigan

Work Experiences

Noah's Ark Lab London, UK Dec. 2022 - Present RESEARCH INTERN (PT)

· Mentor: Jiankang Deng

• Project: Image Generation/Editing via Diffusion Models

PixelShift.AI Shanghai, China May 2020 - Sep. 2020

COMPUTER VISION ALGORITHM INTERN (FT)

- Mentors: Zhiming Ma and Meng Zhang
- Project: Immersive AR application (Google MediaPipe) and deployment of generative models (TFLite)

Publications

Conference -

Controllable Person Image Synthesis with Pose-Constrained Latent Diffusion

Xiao Han, Jiankang Deng, Xiatian Zhu, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

Under Review Oct. 2023

FAME-ViL: Multi-Tasking Vision-Language Model for Heterogeneous Fashion Tasks (Highlight, Top 2.5%)

Xiao Han, Xiatian Zhu, Licheng Yu, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

CVPR 2023 Jun. 2023

FashionViL: Fashion-Focused Vision-and-Language Representation Learning

FCCV 2022 Oct. 2022

Xiao Han, Licheng Yu, Xiatian Zhu, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

UIGR: Unified Interactive Garment Retrieval

CVPRW 2022

Xiao Han, Sen He, Li Zhang, Yi-Zhe Song, Tao Xiang

Jun. 2022

- FashionMMF: A codebase for fashion-related vision-and-language research (based on Meta AI MMF)

 https://github.com/BrandonHanx/mmf and https://github.com/BrandonHanx/FAME-ViL
- Implementation and extension of our paper FashionViL (ECCV 2022) and FAME-ViL (CVPR 2023)

eBayChallenge: A modularized codebase for large-scale product retrieval (based on PyTorch Lightning and Hydra)

- https://github.com/01BB01/eBayChallenge
- Implementation of our solution for eBay eProduct Visual Search Challenge FGVC9 (CVPR2022)

CompFashion: A modularized codebase for text-guided image retrieval (based on vanilla PyTorch)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/CompFashion
- Implementation and extension of our paper UIGR: Unified Interactive Garment Retrieval (CVPRW 2022)

TextReID: A modularized codebase for text-based person search (based on vanilla PyTorch)

- https://github.com/BrandonHanx/TextReID
- Implementation and extension of our paper Text-Based Person Search with Limited Data (BMVC 2021)

	Honors & Awards	
2022	2 nd Place, eBay eProduct Visual Search Challenge - FGVC9 (CVPR2022)	eBay, USA
2021-2024	Faculty of Engineering and Physical Sciences/iFlytek Scholarship	University of Surrey/iFlytek, UK
2019	Chunzhen International Exchange Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2017-2019	3 rd Prize, Academic & Outstanding Student Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2018	Yongping Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2018	3 rd Prize, National Talent Training Base Scholarship	Zhejiang University, China
2018	Honorable Mention Prize, Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM)	COMAP, USA
2017	3 rd Prize, Physics Innovation Competition in Zhejiang Province (Theory Part)	Zhejiang Physical Society, China

Services

Teaching assistant / Demonstrator at University of Surrey

- EEEM071 (2023 Spring) Advanced Topics in Computer Vision and Deep Learning (under Prof. Yi-Zhe Song and Dr. Xiatian Zhu)
- Responsible for the final coursework design (Vehicle ReID) and lab tutorial preparation
- Responsible for demonstrating in lab sessions with 145+ PG/T students with mixed backgrounds
- Responsible for marking the experimental reports and examination papers

Project tutor at University of Surrey

- EEEM004 (2023 Spring) 60 Credit Standard Project (under Dr. Xiatian Zhu)
- Responsible for guiding PG/T final projects "Zero-/Few-shot learning with language supervision"

Conference reviewer

- 6th CVPR Workshop on Computer Vision for Fashion, Art, and Design (CVFAD) 2023
- International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2023
- IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023
- AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2023
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2022
- ACM International Conference on Multimedia (ACM MM) 2022
- IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME) 2022

Journal reviewer

• IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)

Skills

Programming Languages Python, C/C++, MATLAB, ŁTEX, Verilog, JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML/CSS

Frameworks and Tools PyTorch, PyTorch Lightning, TensorFlow, Git, Docker, W&B

Codebases Meta Al MMF, HuggingFace Pipeline (e.g., Transformers/Diffusers), Google MediaPipe, timm

Languages 普通话 Mandarin (native), English (fluent), 한국어 Korean (beginner)

References

Will be provided upon request